Finding Aid for Bach family papers, 1862-1943
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Bach family papers 1862-1943
Bach family
0.4 linear feet and 1 oversize folder
85690 Aa 2 UAm
Ann Arbor, Michigan, family. Family correspondence, photographs, and miscellanea.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was donated by Ellen B. Bach (donor no. 1708 ) and the Bach estate in multiple accessions, 1942-1960.
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Ellen Botsford Bach was a 1901 graduate of the University of Michigan. Her brother Waldo Botsford Bach attended the University of Michigan from 1897 to 1898. In 1898, during the Spanish American War, he served as a private with Co. A, 31st Michigan Infantry.
The collection consists of letters of Ellen Botsford Bach written while touring Europe and while attending the University of Michigan. Her other papers include reminiscences of her early life in Ann Arbor before 1900 and a recipe book. The papers of Waldo Bach consist of letters he wrote while serving in the Spanish American War.
Subjects:
Ann Arbor (Mich.)--History.; Women--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Bach family.; Botsford family.; Cookery.; Daughters of the American Revolution. Sarah Caswell Angell Chapter (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Voyages and travels.; Travelers.; University of Michigan--History.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1901-1910.; World War, 1914-1918.; Spanish-American War, 1898; Europe--Description and travel.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Buildings.; Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Business enterprises.; Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Dwellings.; Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Social life and customs.; Ann Arbor High School (Mich.)--Societies, etc.; Bach, Ellen Botsford, 1877-1960.; Bach, Waldo.; Bach family.; Bach & Abel (Dry goods store: Ann Arbor, Mich.); Bicycles and tricycles.; Boats.; Business enterprises--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; City and town life.; Delta Sigma Nu (Ann Arbor High School); Dry goods stores--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Dwellings--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Farms--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Germany.; Horses.; Interiors--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Military camps.; Picnics.; Soldiers--Michigan.; Tourism; Women.; Zeta Rho (Ann Arbor High School); Spanish-American War, 1898
Contributors:
Bach, Ellen Botsford, 1877-1960.; Bach, Waldo.
Genre Terms:
Cyanotypes.; Photographs.
- Letters of Ellen Botsford Bach written while on European tour
  - August-October 1897 (Box 1)
  - November-December 1897 (Box 1)
  - January-March 1898 (Box 1)
  - April-August 1898 (Box 1)
- Letters of Waldo Bach written while in military service during the Spanish American War
  - May-June 1898 (Box 1)
  - August-October 1898 (Box 1)
- Other materials
  - Letters, 1862-1943 and undated (scattered dates) (Box 1)
  - Reminiscences of Ellen Botsford Bach of early life in Ann Arbor (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous, including article on New Year's calls; history of Sarah Caswell Angell Chapter of the DAR; questionnaire containing recollections of Ellen Bach's UM college days (Box 1)
  - Cookbook of Ellen Bach (Box 1)
  - Land deeds, etc. (Folder UAm)
- Photographs
  - Horses in barnyards (Box 1)
  - Waldo Bach, (Spanish American War), Bach and Abel business, Ann Arbor High School groups (Box 1)
  - Album of Ellen Bach, 1896 containing views of Ann Arbor homes and other buildings, photographs of family and friends, and travel scenes (Box 1)
  - Philip Bach portrait (print) (Folder UAm)